# Rahul Gupta () Featured

Software Development Engineering-Professional seeking roles in Application

Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement

Analysis, Solution

Architecture, Agile, Java, HTML, XML, JavaScript, JSP, JDBC, Spring, Hibernate, Web

Services, Restful



Current Designation: Associate Level 2-Technology.

Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Avizva Solutions Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Delhi Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR, Gurgaon, Noida

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Development Engineering- Professional, Software Developer, Application Programming, Application

Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution

Architecture, Agile, C, Java, HTML, XML, JSP, JavaScript, JDBC, Spring, Hibernate, JAX-WS

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

### Summary

Having hands on Experience on OOP's, Collections, Multithreading & Exceptions Handling.

Have good knowledge of JEE application model to develop web-based solutions using Struts, Spring, Hibernate, Servlet, JSP, JDBC, Oracle (SQL), Tools and IDE.

Hands on Experience in Spring Framework (Spring Core, Spring JDBC, Spring ORM, Spring AOP, Spring Transaction, Spring Security and Spring MVC).

Have good knowledge of Spring Boot.

Experienced in using ORM technologies like Hibernate.

Working Knowledge of Cache (First Level Cache And Second Level Cache) in Hibernate.

Knowledge of Database Tool like mysql (workbench) And Sql-developer.

Having good experience on Web Services, and Restful services.

Good at Xml Technology, XSD, JAX-P, JAX-B, JAX-RPC, Stax, APACHE AXIS2.

## **Work Experience**

Avizva Solutions as Associate Level 2-Technology.

Sep 2020 to Till Date

WellServ is a platform to support WellDyne Member Service Representatives and also administration of WellView Portal Assets (like content etc.) and for operations team to service WellView Members.

WellServ platform will offer the following capabilities:

- 1- Security
- a. Accessing the WellServ through WellDyne Active Directory
- b. A fine-grained Authorization Model for both Functions and Data across Administration and Operations team
- 2- Member Management
- a. Searching a member by Name, Member ID, Phone, Rx Number, Order Number, Claim Number, MFI or Email. This will return all Membership (including members not yet migrated to WellView)
- b. Viewing Member's eligibility history
- c. Access to key Member Data: Claims, Prescriptions and Orders

- d. Provide key actions for Members.
- e. Send custom notifications to Members
- 3- Impersonate a Member (as read only)
- 4- Call Management
- a. Workflow to manage Inbound and Outbound call from Call Start through End
- b. Verify/Authenticate Members, Pharmacies, Doctors, Third Parties and Clients
- c. HIPPA Authorization
- d. Auto Tracking/Auditing of calls as Member Service Representative looks up information on the system
- e. Call End Workflow for taking Call Reason Codes, Notes and assignment of tasks through Service Now to other
- WellDyne Groups as well as capturing mood and resolution status for caller
- 5- Call Management will cover the following flows: Member, Pharmacy, Client, Third Parties, Doctors and Others Calls. The sequence of steps, Pane Layout, and Data Authorization Steps will be different for the caller types. For Member and Pharmacy, Functions covered are covered in Member Management Section above.
- 6- Integration of following functions with existing systems
- a. WellConnect Eligibility Determination and Enrollment
- b. Display PA authorization status for Member
- c. Search and Open tickets for Member on Service Now
- 7- Content Management
- a. Manage WellView Alerts and Splash Pages by CAG
- b. Manage CAG Contact information
- c. CAG logo management for White Labeled Clients
- 8- Reports
- a. View Statistics and Trends on various parameters such as Category and Reasons, Mood etc.

Fiserv India Pvt. Ltd as Software Development Engineering- Professional (Java) Feb 2019 to Sep 2020

Lince Soft Solutions Pvt. Ltd. as Java Developer Jul 2016 to Feb 2019

### **Education**

UG: BCA (Computers) from Chhatrapati Shahu Ji Maharaj University (CSJMU) in 2013

PG: MCA (Computers) from Banaras Hindu University (BHU), Varanasi in 2016

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
HTML,XML			
JSON			
JavaScript			
JAX-RPC (SI), JAX-WS			
JAX-RS			
JAX-B, JAX-P			
Servlet 2.5, JSP 2.0			
WINDOWS, LINUX			
C, JAVA			
JDBC, JNDI			
spring boot			
Oracle10g, SQL, PL/SQL, MySQL			
Tomcat, JBoss And Wildfly			
SVN			

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=21db5dcd6e6888dd35edc0f3cf6dc2180a5c0c004e450a14501144510e...

LOG4J
MAVEN
Eclipse, STS, Altova xmlspy
Version One, Red mine , JIRA
JUNIT
Oracle Sql-developer
SOAP-UI
TANDEM

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			

# **Projects**

Project Title: Welldyne-Wellserv-CRM

Client: WellDyneRx, U.S

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Sep 2020 - Till Date
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: WellServ is a platform to support WellDyne Member Service Representatives and also administration of WellView Portal Assets (like content etc.) and for operations team to service WellView Members.

WellServ platform will offer the following capabilities:

- 1- Security
- a. Accessing the WellServ through WellDyne Active Directory
- b. A fine-grained Authorization Model for both Functions and Data across Administration and Operations team
- 2- Member Management
- a. Searching a member by Name, Member ID, Phone, Rx Number, Order Number, Claim Number, MFI or Email. This will return all Membership (including members not yet migrated to WellView)
- b. Viewing Members eligibility history
- c. Access to key Member Data: Claims, Prescriptions and Orders
- d. Provide key actions for Members.
- e. Send custom notifications to Members
- 3- Impersonate a Member (as read only)
- 4- Call Management
- a. Workflow to manage Inbound and Outbound call from Call Start through End
- b. Verify/Authenticate Members, Pharmacies,

Project Title: IC (Implementation Console)

Client: Fiserv

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Feb 2019 - Till Date
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 12

Skill Used: Java 7, 8, Struts, Spring 4.0, Hibernate 4.3.0, Design

Patterns, JAX-RS, JSP 2.0, SVN, Eclipse, And JOBSS

AS7, EAP, Tandem, Async api, Java Script, Oracle DB

Project Details: Implementation Console is a feature provided to manage the card, ATM and POS machine Automatically. This service is very high volume service, For every Fiserv Client (like Bank for all countries) login application will manage tha card details and his networks(Visa, Master, Mestro etc..) also same for Terminal Machine(ATM) and POS Machine. This service will be given in two formats in Web services and other in Rest Services.

For desktop login api will try get the complete client details through web services and rest services both. Api is intelligent enough to identify the client and provide the customer details.

Project Title: LRMS (Loyalty Rewards Management System)

Client: Carter Bank & Trust, US Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Nov 2017 - Feb 2019 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Team Size: 5

Skill Used: JAX-WS, JAX-RS, Spring 4.0, Hibernate 4.3.0, Oracle10g, Design Patterns, Java1.7, JSP 2.0, SVN, Maven, Eclipse, and Tomcat Server

Project Details: LRMS is a feature provided to customer to check the reward points earned by the card holder by login into the net banking. This service is very high volume service, For every user login application will load the Customer reward point details to the user. This service will be given in two formats in Web services and other in Rest Services.

For desktop login api will try get the complete customer details through web services, if the customer login through the mobile the service will get the details using rest services. Api is intelligent enough to identify the client and provide the customer details.

### **Affirmative Action**

### **Work Authorization**

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time